<dashboard>
  <label>Index "Ballast" Overview</label>

  <search id="ballast_cumulative">
    <query>
`fb_data_from_today` `_fb_summary_recs(*)`
| eval state=case(state="hot", "home", state="warm", "home", 1=1, state)
|  stats sum(sizeOnDiskMB) AS total, sum(eval(if(endEpoch>now(), sizeOnDiskMB, 0))) AS ballast by state, splunk_server, index 
| fillnull value=0 ballast | eval live=total-ballast
    </query>
  </search>

  <row>
    <html>
<div id="fire_brigade_help">
As described in the help for the <a
href="/app/fire_brigade/bucket_lifecycle">Bucket Lifecycle</a> dashboard,
indexing buckets typically move through several phases in their life span. The
mechanisms which work to tranition these buckets do so based upon the age of
the events in the bucket (as measured by the most recent <em>event
time</em>). This is true even for size-based retention rules.
<p />
The concept of index ballast is a bucket or set of buckets that have events
from the future. Since Splunk is not a time machine, the origin of these
"future" events typically lies in misconfiguration. Time stamps may be
incorrectly parsed, or time zones improperly identified. When retention rules
require that a bucket be moved, these "ballast" buckets won't be selected,
since they are not the oldest buckets in the collection (unless of course
<em>all</em> of the buckets in the index have future time stamps). For
space-based rules, these buckets become more problematic, since they're taking
up room that might be recycled for use by other (newly arrived) data. The
impact of these buckets is greater the further into the future their events
occur.
<p />
Another source of "ballast" is buckets in the thawed state. These arise from
administrative action (deliberately restoring frozen buckets into a searchable
state) and further, <em>require</em> adminstrative action to remove them once
they're no longer needed. They do not count against the index's space
allocation (as far as Splunk is concerned), but they do take up space on the
partition.
<p />
This dashboard attempts to call out the amount of disk space occupied by
ballast buckets of either kind. The Home path (hot and warm states) is shown
separately from the Cold path. This is for sites that may be making use of
mixed media for index storage. A separate tally appears for buckets in the
thawed state, and finally a combined tally across all indexers.
<p />
The two charts in the bottom section of the page break out the ballast
sums. The first, <em>Ballast by Indexer</em>, is divided by splunk_sever
(indexing host). On the right is a split by index name in the chart titled
<em>Ballast by Index</em>. Each of these provide drilldown functionality to
pages that will provide more detail.
</div>
    </html>
  </row>

  <row>
    <single>
      <title>Home Path (Hot + Warm) Ballast</title>
      <option name="link.visible">false</option>
      <search base="ballast_cumulative">
	<query>search state="home" | stats sum(ballast) AS ballast
| `_fb_mbytes_pretty(ballast)`</query>
      </search>
    </single>

    <single>
      <title>Cold Path Ballast</title>
      <option name="link.visible">false</option>
      <option name="field">ballast</option>
      <search base="ballast_cumulative">
	<query>search state="cold" | stats count, sum(ballast) AS ballast
| fillnull value=0 ballast
| `_fb_mbytes_pretty(ballast)`</query>
      </search>
    </single>

    <single>
      <title>Thawed Data</title>
      <option name="link.visible">false</option>
      <search base="ballast_cumulative">
	<query>search state="thawed" | stats sum(ballast) AS ballast
| `_fb_mbytes_pretty(ballast)`</query>
      </search>
    </single>

    <single>
      <title>Total Burden</title>
      <option name="link.visible">false</option>
      <option name="underLabel">Ballast + Thawed</option>
      <search base="ballast_cumulative">
	<query>stats sum(eval(if(state="thawed", total, ballast))) AS ballast
| `_fb_mbytes_pretty(ballast)`</query>
      </search>
    </single>
  </row>

  <!-- slice and dice -->
  <row>
    <chart>
      <title>Ballast by Indexer</title>
      <option name="link.visible">false</option>
      <option name="charting.chart">column</option>
      <option name="charting.legend.placement">none</option>
      <search base="ballast_cumulative">
	<query>stats sum(ballast) AS ballast by splunk_server</query>
      </search>
      <drilldown>
	<link><![CDATA[/app/fire_brigade/host_overview?form.host=$click.value$]]>
	</link>
      </drilldown>
    </chart>
    <chart>
      <title>Ballast by Index</title>
      <option name="link.visible">false</option>
      <option name="charting.chart">column</option>
      <option name="charting.legend.placement">none</option>
      <search base="ballast_cumulative">
	<query>stats sum(ballast) AS ballast by index</query>
      </search>
      <drilldown>
	<link><![CDATA[/app/fire_brigade/index_overview?form.index=$click.value$]]>  
	</link>
      </drilldown>
    </chart>
  </row>

</dashboard>
