<form class="formsearch">
  <label>Bucket Lifecycle</label>

  <searchTemplate>`fb_bucket_transitions($host$, $stage$)` `_fb_bucket_lifecycle_index_term($index$)` | `fb_bucket_transition_pp`</searchTemplate>
  <fieldset>
    <input type="dropdown" token="host" searchWhenChanged="true">
      <label>Host</label>
      <populatingSearch fieldForValue="orig_host" fieldForLabel="orig_host">| inputlookup fb_hostname_index_cache | dedup orig_host | sort orig_host</populatingSearch>
    </input>
    <input type="dropdown" token="index" searchWhenChanged="true">
      <label>Index</label>
      <choice value="*">All indexes</choice>
      <default>*</default>
      <populatingSearch fieldForValue="orig_index" fieldForLabel="orig_index">| inputlookup fb_hostname_index_cache | search orig_host=$host$ | dedup orig_index | sort orig_index</populatingSearch>
    </input>
    <input type="dropdown" token="stage" searchWhenChanged="true">
      <label>State Transition</label>
      <default>New Hot Buckets</default>
      <choice value="kindle">New Hot Buckets</choice>
      <choice value="cool">Hot -> Warm</choice>
      <choice value="chill">Warm -> Cold</choice>
      <choice value="freeze">Cold -> Frozen</choice>
      <choice value="minify">Shrink Bucket</choice>
      <choice value="*">All State Transitions</choice>
    </input>
    <input type="time" />
  </fieldset>

  <row>
    <html>
<div id="fire_brigade_help">
During the normal course of operation, Splunk will transition index
buckets through several states. New buckets start out in the "hot"
state, and are transitioned through "warm" to "cold" and ultimately
the "freeze" transition (which in the default case, is deletion).
Each bucket transition emits a signature log event to the
<code>splunkd.log</code> written into the <code>_internal</code>
index.
<p/>
This dashboard shows a summary of, as well as the raw form of the
events themselves. Selecting "All State Transitions" from the pulldown
menu will show all states, while the other menu items focus on a
particular transition.
<p/>
<h3>New Hot Buckets</h3>
Buckets are first created in the "hot" state. This bucket state is
writable, and is where all new events arrive. When possible, the event
time of the newly arrived event (the one which prompted creation of
the new hot bucket) is displayed. This can help spot time parsing
issues, particularly if the bucket is a "quarantine hot" bucket.
<p/>
<h3>Hot -> Warm</h3>
When buckets change state from hot to warm, they are no longer being
written to. These are still searchable (like any bucket bar those
which are frozen), but their contents are now static. This can occur
for a number of reasons; this dashboard attempts to iterate some of
those possibilities.
<ul>
  <li>
  Too Many Hot Buckets - There are more than the
  configured maximum of hot buckets presently open. If events are
  arriving from disparate time frames, such as environments without
  time synchronization, or when a new forwarder is provisioned and its
  historical data is indexed, this can cause multiple hot buckets to
  be open at once. Too many, and Splunk will close one of the least
  recently used.
  </li>
  <li>
  Bucket Hit Max Size - This is the case when a bucket
  tops out at its configured max size.
  </li>
  <li>
  (Cluster) Restart - When Splunk restarts, whether the rolling
  restart of a cluster, or a simple restart of an individual indexer,
  all hot buckets are automatically rolled to the warm state when
  Splunk comes back up.
  </li>
  <li>
  Bucket Idle Too Long - If a hot bucket sits idle with no new
  events for too long, it will automatically be rolled from hot to warm.
  </li>
</ul>
<p/>
<h3>Warm -> Cold</h3>
The "cold" bucket state is the same as warm--the bucket is static, and
searchable--but it's the first opportunity to change the storage
location of the bucket. Hot and warm buckets live in the same
directory (the <code>homePath</code>), but cold buckets are stored in
the <code>coldPath</code>. This distinction allows for changing the
storage medium, to a collection of "big, slow disks", for example.
Transitions from warm to cold will typically take place based on a
<i>count</i> basis. That is, the default parameters make it most
likely for a bucket to be moved from warm to cold simply because there
are too many warm buckets.
<p/>
<h3>Cold -> Frozen</h3>
This state transition renders a bucket unsearchable. With default
parameters, the bucket is simply deleted. If a script
(<code>coldToFrozenScript</code>) or a target directory
(<code>coldToFrozenDir</code>) is provided, buckets will transition
from cold to frozen gracefully, rather than being deleted. In the case
of a directory target, the index files are removed from the bucket,
leaving behind only the journaled raw data. This raw data allows the
bucket to be rebuilt if needed, see the Splunk Documentation <a
href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/latest/Indexer/RestoreArchivedData">here</a>
for more info.
<p/>
<h3>Minify</h3>
This state transition relates to new features provided in the 6.4 release of
Splunk. This feature, called <a href="docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/latest/Indexer/Reducetsidxdiskusage">TSIDX reduction</a>, replaces the TSIDX files
in indexing buckets with "minified" versions that provide space savings in
exchange for reduced performance. This enables Splunk administrators to make
better use of their storage for long-term search access. Either	<i>warm</i> or
<i>cold</i> buckets are eligible to be reduced in this way.
</div>
    </html>
  </row>

  <row>
    <table>
      <title>Summary of Bucket Events</title>
      <option name="link.visible">false</option>
      <option name="drilldown">row</option>
      <drilldown>
        <link><![CDATA[
/app/fire_brigade/lolrus?form.host=$form.host$&form.index=$row.Index$&form.bucket_id=$row.Bucket ID$]]>
	</link>
      </drilldown>
    </table>
  </row>

  <row>
    <event>
      <title>Matching Raw Events</title>
      <option name="link.visible">false</option>
      <option name="type">raw</option>
    </event>
  </row>

</form>
