<dashboard>
  <label>Matrix Overview (REST)</label>

  <row>
    <html>
<div id="fire_brigade_help">
<p/>
This dashboard is intended to show the overall status of the
indexers in the Splunk environment.
<p/>
Instead of using the <code>dbinspect</code> mechanism like the other
dashboards within Fire Brigade, this view expressly uses <i>only</i>
the REST API. As such, the information on this dashboard is current
from the time the search is run, not subject to any delay. Also,
because it relies upon the REST API, it spans all of the hosts which
are distributed search peers, not only those which have been
instrumented with the <em>Technology Add-on for Fire Brigade</em>.
<p/>
The top table focuses on the disk space constraints on all of the
indexes, on all of the search peers. The first value in each cell is
the current usage, given in megabytes. After the slash is shown the
<code>maxTotalDataSizeMB</code> setting for the index. The percentage
value shown is the ratio of these tow values. If a cell is empty, the
corresponding index on the host (row header) is also
empty. <strong>Note:</strong> If tired storage usage based on
<code>homePath</code> (<em>homePath.maxDataSizeMB</em>) and
<code>coldPath</code> (<em>coldPath.maxDataSizeMB</em>) is used, the
maximum value shown (on the right hand side of the slash) is the
<em>lesser</em> of the sum of the two path maximums vs. the combined
maximum. If <i>volume-based</i> retention is used, the limits for
those settings may override what is shown here.
<p/>
The bottom table helps to illustrate the <em>span</em> of events in
the index.  The first value in each cell shows the amount of time
between the earliest event and the latest event in the index
(elsewhere called "Maximal Span"), in a human readable format. The
second string is the human-readable form of the
<code>frozenTimePeriodInSecs</code> setting for the index. The default
value is approximately six years (2184 days), but many sites will set
this to a specific value to target a specific
SLA. <strong>Note:</strong> The format for the values in these cells
is &lt;days&gt;+&lt;hours&gt;:&lt;minutes&gt;:&lt;seconds&gt;.
</div>
    </html>
  </row>

  <row>
    <table>
      <title>Matrix View - Index Capacity</title>
      <option name="link.visible">false</option>
      <option name="drilldown">row</option>
      <searchString>
| rest /services/data/indexes search="totalEventCount!=0"
| `_fb_null_hot_cold_max`
| eval roof=min((coalesce('homePath.maxDataSizeMB', 4294967295) +
                 coalesce('coldPath.maxDataSizeMB', 4294967295)),
                maxTotalDataSizeMB)
| eval span=tostring(currentDBSizeMB) + " / " +
    tostring(roof) + " MB (" +
    tostring(round(currentDBSizeMB * 100 / roof)) + "%)"
| chart first(span) over splunk_server by title
| rename splunk_server AS Indexer
      </searchString>

      <drilldown>
        <link field="Indexer"><![CDATA[/app/fire_brigade/host_overview?form.host=$click.value$]]></link>
        <link><![CDATA[/app/fire_brigade/retention_size?form.host=$row.Indexer$&form.index=$click.name2$]]></link>
      </drilldown>
    </table>
  </row>

  <row>
    <table>
      <title>Matrix View - Index Retention</title>
      <option name="link.visible">false</option>
      <option name="drilldown">row</option>
      <searchString>
| rest /services/data/indexes search="totalEventCount!=0"
| eval minTime=round(strptime(minTime, "%Y-%m-%dT%H:%M:%S%z"))
| eval maxTime=round(strptime(maxTime, "%Y-%m-%dT%H:%M:%S%z"))
| eval span=tostring(maxTime-minTime, "duration") + " / " +
    tostring(frozenTimePeriodInSecs, "duration")
| chart first(span) over splunk_server by title
| rename splunk_server AS Indexer
      </searchString>

      <drilldown>
        <link field="Indexer"><![CDATA[/app/fire_brigade/host_overview?form.host=$click.value$]]></link>
        <link><![CDATA[/app/fire_brigade/retention_age?form.host=$row.Indexer$&form.index=$click.name2$]]></link>
      </drilldown>
    </table>
  </row>

</dashboard>
